Guide to the Slavery Miscellaneous Manuscripts Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Slavery Miscellaneous Manuscripts collection
1780-1865
MS 717
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1
(3 boxes)
An artificial collection of volumes, tracts, deeds, and clippings on the topic of slavery. A seven volume composition of material on slavery and abolition, and a "Census of the Slaves in Chester County, Pennsylvania" are included.
Existence and Location of Copies
Entire collection also available on microfilm (1,771 frames on 3 reels, 35mm.) from Scholarly Resources, Inc., Wilmington, Delaware.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
The entire collection is available on microfilm. Patrons must use FILM HM 166 instead of the originals.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of a variety of items from different sources concerned with slavery, especially in the United States. The materials range in date from 1780 to the 1960s.
The largest section of the collection is made up of seven scrapbooks titled "Tracts on Slavery in the United States, and on the U.S. Constitution and Organic Laws." They contain manuscript writings, printed pamphlets and tracts, and newspaper clippings on the subject of slavery and abolitionism, with most of the material dating from the 1850s and 1860s. The original compiler is unknown. The volumes were given to Yale University from the library of Louis R. Ehrich by his son Walter L. Ehrich in 1926.
The next item is a manuscript book containing records of punishments administered to slaves in a South American mining camp. 177 slaves are named, the reason for their punishment are given, and the method of punishment is listed. The records, which are kept in English, cover the years 1836-1847. The volume was given to Yale University by Stuart W. Jackson in 1937.
The following folder contains twenty deeds for slaves, dating from 1783 to 1848. They were acquired by the University from a variety of sources. The deeds come from North Carolina, Maryland, Kentucky, Alabama, and Tennessee. The next folder contains nine newspaper clippings from the 1840s through the 1860s relating to the anti-slavery movement in Kansas, New Hampshire, Tennessee, Texas, and Virginia.
The final item is a manuscript book containing the census of slaves in Chester County, Pennsylvania, from 1780 to 1815. This was given to Yale University by Abel Cary Thomas in 1936.
African Americans; Slavery -- United States; Slavery; Chester County (Pa.); United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; Slave records
- Inventory
  - "Tracts on Slavery in the United States, and on the U.S. Constitution and Organic Laws", [ca. 1850-1860]
    - Vols. 1-2 (Box 1, Folder 1, Reel 1U)
    - Vols. 3-4 (Box 1, Folder 2, Reel 1U, Reel 2U)
    - Vols. 5-6 (Box 1, Folder 3, Reel 2U)
    - Vol. 7 (Box 2, Folder 4, Reel 2U)
  - Manuscript book of punishments administered to slaves in a South American mining camp, 1836-1847 (Box 2, Folder 5, Reel 3U)
  - 20 slave deeds, 1783-1848 (Box 2, Folder 6, Reel 3U)
  - 9 newspaper clippings concerning slavery, 1842-[1860?] (Box 2, Folder 7, Reel 3U)
  - "A Census of the Slaves in Chester County, Pennsylvania, 1780-1815 (Box 3, Folder 8, Reel 3U)